import 'package:quiz_app_tutorial/models/question.dart';

const List<Question> geoQuestions = [
  Question(
    question: '1. Which river is the longest in the world?',
    correctAnswerIndex: 0,
    options: [
      'a) Nile',
      'b) Amazon',
      'c) Yangtze',
      'd) Mississippi',
    ],
  ),
  Question(
    question: '2. What is the capital city of France?',
    correctAnswerIndex: 2,
    options: [
      'a) Berlin',
      'b) London',
      'c) Paris',
      'd) Madrid',
    ],
  ),
  Question(
    question: '3. In which continent is the Sahara Desert located?',
    correctAnswerIndex: 1,
    options: [
      'a) Asia',
      'b) Africa',
      'c) South America',
      'd) Australia',
    ],
  ),
  Question(
    question: '4. What is the highest mountain in the world?',
    correctAnswerIndex: 2,
    options: [
      'a) Mount Kilimanjaro',
      'b) Mount Elbrus',
      'c) Mount Everest',
      'd) Mount McKinley',
    ],
  ),
  Question(
    question: '5. Which country is known as the Land of the Rising Sun?',
    correctAnswerIndex: 0,
    options: [
      'a) Japan',
      'b) China',
      'c) South Korea',
      'd) Vietnam',
    ],
  ),
  Question(
    question: '6. What is the largest ocean on Earth?',
    correctAnswerIndex: 1,
    options: [
      'a) Atlantic Ocean',
      'b) Pacific Ocean',
      'c) Indian Ocean',
      'd) Southern Ocean',
    ],
  ),
  Question(
    question: '7. Which country is famous for its pyramids?',
    correctAnswerIndex: 2,
    options: [
      'a) Greece',
      'b) Mexico',
      'c) Egypt',
      'd) Peru',
    ],
  ),
  Question(
    question: '8. What is the capital city of Australia?',
    correctAnswerIndex: 3,
    options: [
      'a) Sydney',
      'b) Melbourne',
      'c) Brisbane',
      'd) Canberra',
    ],
  ),
  Question(
    question: '9. Which river flows through the Grand Canyon?',
    correctAnswerIndex: 0,
    options: [
      'a) Colorado River',
      'b) Amazon River',
      'c) Thames River',
      'd) Nile River',
    ],
  ),
  Question(
    question: '10. In which country can you find the Great Barrier Reef?',
    correctAnswerIndex: 1,
    options: [
      'a) Mexico',
      'b) Australia',
      'c) Indonesia',
      'd) Brazil',
    ],
  ),
];
